Daniel French

Details

College Station 832-316-7138 dan.r.french@sbcglobal.net

Links

<u>Portfolio</u>

Linkedin

GitHub

Codewars

Skills

C#

HTML5

CSS

GitHub

MySQL

ASP.NET

Microsoft Excel

Summary

I am a hardworking self-starter with a passion for learning, solving problems and analyzing information. I am proficient in C# and other programming languages that power some of the most useful and problem solving features on the web. I also have experience with integrating relational databases like MySQL with web applications.

Education

TrueCoders Full Stack Software Engineering Program, Birmingham

MAY 2023 - JUNE 2023

- Project-based training in programming languages and other technical skills, such as SQL, C#, .NET Core, Git, ASP.NET MVC, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- These skills were developed by building multiple C# and SQL projects in Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code
- C# and SQL Projects were tracked in Git and GitHub for source control
- Managed SQL databases using the CRUD operations in MySQL

Bachelor of Business Administration in Marketing, Texas A&M University-Kingsville, Kingsville

MAY 2005 - DECEMBER 2008

- Gained a solid foundation in marketing principles such as market research, consumer behavior and market segmentation
- Learned personal sales skills and techniques
- Learned strategies for market entry and analyzing strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats in competitive markets
- Accounting Principles
- Graduated with honors (3.6 G.P.A.)

Experience

Software Developer, Centennial Arts, Bryan

JANUARY 2024 - PRESENT

- Designing and re-designing customer websites in WordPress using AIT themes
- Installing WordPress packages and plugins on FreeBSD operating system through command line
- Exporting blogs in .xml from existing sites, then editing and importing to newly created sites
- Logging work and communicating progress on customer website projects and other issues using Jira ticketing system
- Answering inbound customer calls using Linphone VoIP

Realtor, Keller Williams Realty Brazos Valley, College Station

APRIL 2021 - OCTOBER 2023

- Marketing our team's real estate services through social media, direct mail campaigns, and outbound phone calls
- Preparing and presenting pricing analyses and marketing strategies to prospective listing clients
- Showing properties to prospective buyers
- Maintaining transaction paperwork such as contract addenda, listing agreements, buyer's representation agreements, etc.
- Guiding clients through the process of buying/leasing or selling real estate

Courier, FedEx Express, College Station

JUNE 2014 - APRIL 2023

- Responsible for safely and efficiently sorting and delivering packages in College Station, TX and surrounding areas
- Led the team responsible for receiving and delivering First Overnight packages
- Supervised A.M. unloading activities and ensured a successful flow rate of packages per hour